Now I know what you're thinking.
무슨 생각 하는지 알아요
We've been building environments for so long.
우린 오랫동안 환경을 만들었어요
Are we not done yet?
아직 안 끝났어요?
We're almost done.
거의 다 됐어요
There's two more steps to go, and then we are through with environment setup and onto projects.
두 단계가 더 있어요 환경 셋업을 거쳐 프로젝트로 넘어가죠
So the next thing we have to do is set up our keys to use open AI so that we can connect from our JupyterLab
다음으로 할 일은 오픈 인공지능을 사용할 키를 설정하는 겁니다 유피터랩 환경에서 연결해
environment to run with some of the most powerful models on the planet.
지구에서 가장 강력한 모델로 실행할 수 있도록요
Uh, if you go to the Readme, uh, in our GitHub repository and you scroll down a little bit, we'll
깃허브 리포지토리의 리드미로 가셔서 스크롤을 좀 내리시면 주요 공급자로
get to the point where there are the links to the major providers, and we're just going to be using
가는 링크가 있는 곳으로 갈 수 있습니다 이번 주에는 오픈 인공 지능을 사용할
open AI for this week.
거예요 비트지능
And if you click on that link, it will take us to the open AI page.
그 링크를 클릭하면 열린 인공지능 페이지가 나와요
If you've never been before, you will have to sign up or sign in using Google credentials or creating
처음 가보는 분이라면 구글 자격 증명을 이용해 가입하거나 로그인해야 합니다 계정을
an account.
만들거나요
Now, before we go further, I have to explain something that's pretty confusing, which does sometimes,
더 진행하기 전에 혼란스러운 점을 설명할게요 사람들이
uh, throw people all of the major closed source providers like OpenAI and anthropic for Cloud and Google
헷갈릴 때가 있어요 주요 비공개 소스 공급자 오픈AI나 클라우드용 인스로픽 제미니의 구글 같은 두 가지 유형의
for Gemini have two different types of plan that are completely separate and don't have any relationship
사업 계획이 완전히 분리되어 서로 아무런 관련이 없다는 점이죠
One of them relates to their web tools, the front end tools, which you can use to chat with like famously
그중 하나는 웹 도구와 관련된 프런트엔드 도구입니다 유명한 챗GPT와 채팅할 때 사용할 수 있죠
ChatGPT that we all know well.
우리 모두 잘 아는 거예요
ChatGPT has a pro plan that you can pay for if you want to, to be able to use some of the latest models
챗GPT는 프로 플랜을 결제해 두었기 때문에 나중에 살펴볼 최신 모델을 사용할 수
that we'll look at later, like, oh one preview and GPT four with canvas and others.
있습니다 예를 들어 프리뷰 1개와 캔버스 4개 등을요
Uh, that needs a pro plan in some cases.
프로의 계획이 필요한 경우도 있어요
Uh, and the Pro plan costs about $20 a month in the US and similar pricing in other regions.
프로 계획의 미국 요금은 월 20달러 정도고 다른 지역도 가격은 비슷해요
Um, a fixed monthly price, and then you have almost unlimited access to those models.
고정된 월 단가를 제공하고 그런 모델에 거의 무제한으로 접근할 수 있어요
The same is true for anthropic.
인류학도 마찬가지예요
Uh, same same kind of thing.
늘 똑같죠
And, uh, Google Gemini also.
구글에서 제미니도 검색해 보세요
But this is entirely separate to the API world.
이건 API 세계와는 완전히 별개예요
The API world is where you can use.
API 세계를 이용하세요
You can call out to the model directly using code, and it's running on the cloud, and it will respond
코드를 이용해 모델에 직접 호출할 수 있고 클라우드에서 실행되고 있고 여러분의 질문에 대한
with answers to your questions.
답변으로 응답할 거예요
It's a different type of pricing plan.
가격 계획이 달라요
It is there's no monthly subscription.
월간 구독이 안 돼요
There's no no payment whatsoever monthly.
매달 지급되는 건 없어요
But you do have to pay per API request.
API 요청당 돈을 내야 해요
It's a pay per request situation, and the payment per request will talk more detail about API costs
요청당 지불 상황입니다 요청당 지불은 나중에 API 비용에 대해 더 자세히 말씀드리죠
later.
하지만 이 과목에서 진행하는 프로젝트치고는 너무 작아요
For most of the projects, except where I will mention otherwise, it is a fraction of a cent it is
언급할 부분을 제외하고 대부분의 프로젝트에서 1센트도 안 돼요 그러니
tiny, so there is really no harm in trying out some of these APIs and it gets you such power, gives
이런 API를 시도해 보는 건 해가 될 게 없죠 엄청난 힘을 얻고 굉장한 모델에 엑세스 권한을 주니까요
you access to such incredible models, even though some of the models will use their open source are
오픈 소스를 사용하는 모델은 아주 강력하지만요
These frontier closed source models are super powerful, as you will see, and so it makes sense that
이러한 프런티어 폐쇄 소스 모델은 매우 강력합니다. 이러한 반응을 생성하기 위해
you have to pay a small amount for the compute that goes behind the processing to to generate these
프로세싱 뒤에 있는 컴퓨트에 적은 돈을 지불해야 하는 것은 당연하죠.
But having said that, there is a hitch.
하지만 문제가 있어요
There is something about this pricing, uh, which is uh, in some cases it's uh, it's new and it may
이 가격 책정에는 뭔가가 있어요 어떤 경우에는 새롭고 지역에
be different in different regions, but certainly for me and for, for OpenAI, uh, they have a minimum
따라 다를 수도 있지만 저와 OpenAI는 API 사용을 위해 최소로
that you have to put down to use the API.
책정돼 있어요
And in my case right now it is a $5 minimum.
제 경우엔 최소 5달러가 필요해요
So you have to put in at least $5.
그래서 적어도 5달러는 넣어야 해요 Put
And then as you use the API, you'll start to charge down against that $5.
그리고 API 사용 시 5달러로 요금을 낮추기 시작하죠
We're not going to use we're going to use a fraction of that and this entire course, uh, but there'll
이 강의에선 그 일부를 사용하지 않을 겁니다 하지만 그 5달러를
be plenty of other ways that you can use that $5.
사용할 방법은 많아요
I assure you.
장담해요
There are so many projects will build.
앞으로 할 일이 많아요
There'll be so many exercises for you for real, useful things, ways that you'll be able to spend that
정말 유용한 것들을 위한 많은 연습이 있을 겁니다 그 시간을 유용하게 쓰고 좋은
and have a good outcome from it.
결과를 얻는 방법이죠
So my sales pitch to you would be that it is well worth it.
제 영업 전략은 그럴 가치가 있다는 거예요
I would do it, but it is, of course a personal choice.
전 하고 싶지만 물론 개인적 선택이죠
If you don't feel comfortable putting down the $5 or you'd rather not, that's fine.
5달러를 내기 불편하거나 내기 싫으면 안 내도 돼요
You can watch me as I go through the exercises, and what I'll do is I'll show you a way that you can
제가 연습하는 걸 보세요 오픈 소스 모델을 사용하는 방법을
use open source models.
보여드릴게요
Instead, we'll be able to use a llama.
대신 라마를 이용하면 돼요
The thing that we did at the very, very start, and you'll be able to use that as an alternative to
우리가 초창기에 했던 것과 같은 거예요 개척자 모델을 대체할
using a frontier model.
수 있을 거예요
Now, the results, of course, are not going to be the same.
물론 결과는 똑같지 않을 거예요
The it's a, uh, the llama models will be using as like a 2 billion parameter model, uh, compared
라마 모델은 20억 개의 매개 변수 모델을 사용할 겁니다 GPT 4와 비교해서요
to GPT four, that is rumored to be about 10 trillion parameters, uh, perhaps like 10,000 times as
소문에 따르면 10조 개의 매개 변수가 있다고 합니다 아마 10,000배 정도 더 많을 거예요
many.
품질이 다른 모델이지만 5달러는 선불로 주셔야 해요 Put it's go
So that's the decision for you.
그게 당신 결정이에요
And again I my my take is that it is worth it.
다시 말하지만 그럴 가치가 있어요
So in order to do this though, what you need to do is once you've come into the OpenAI platform, you've
이걸 하려면 오픈AI 플랫폼에 들어왔을 때 로그인하면 이 지점에
logged in, you've got to this point.
도달해야 해요
There's just two things you have to do.
두 가지만 하면 돼요
You first have to go to the settings button up here.
먼저 여기 위에 설정 단추로 가야 해요
And on settings over here you go to billing and on billing.
설정에서 계산을 하고 계산을 해요
This is where you need to have some credit balance to be able to use the GPT four zero.
GPT 40을 사용하려면 신용 잔고가 어느 정도 있어야 하죠
And the minimum that it will take is $5.
최소 5달러는 들 거예요
You have to press add to credit balance and then punch in a credit card.
신용 잔액 추가 누르고 신용카드 입력해요
And it will take $5 and keep auto recharge off.
5달러면 되고 자동 재충전도 돼요
You don't want them snapping from your card without your permission.
허가 없이 카드에서 카드를 뽑으면 안 되니까요
As I say this, this has been it.
말씀드린 대로 이게 다예요
I use it all the time, and I barely manage to get beyond a few cents a day because we use the GPT four
저도 항상 사용하지만 하루에 몇 센트 이상 쓸 수 있는 것도 아닙니다 GPT 4 미니를 저렴한 버전으로
mini, the cheap version, almost exclusively on this project, on this course.
사용하는데 이 코스에서 이 프로젝트에서 거의 독점적으로 사용하고 있죠
So.
그래서요?
So this $5 is more than enough and you'll be able to put it to fine use, I assure you.
이 5달러면 충분하고도 남아요 좋은 일에 쓰실 수 있을 거예요 장담해요 Put
So if you are comfortable doing this then go ahead, go to billing, put on your $5.
이렇게 하는 게 괜찮으면 계산대로 가서 5달러를 내요 Put it's go
And then the next thing is to go to dashboard over here and then down to API keys here.
다음은 이쪽 대시보드로 가서 API 키로 내려가죠
And then you have to come here and press this create new secret key button right here.
그런 다음 여기로 와서 이걸 눌러야 해요 새 비밀 키 생성하기요
Uh, you have it set to you.
본인에게 맞춰져 있네요
You can give it a name if you wish.
이름을 지어 줘도 돼요
You give permissions all and then you press the Create Secret key button.
모두 허가를 내린 다음 비밀 키 생성 버튼을 누르세요
And when you do that, it's going to show you a new secret key that you will have created.
그렇게 하면 여러분이 만들게 될 새 비밀 키가 나타나요
And it will give you a chance to copy that secret key into your clipboard.
비밀 열쇠를 클립보드에 복사할 기회도 되고요
And you need to do that because it won't let you ever see it again.
다시는 볼 수 없을 테니 그렇게 해야 해요
This is the most you'll ever see of that secret key again.
이게 그 비밀 열쇠의 마지막 모습일 거예요
It is your secret and you have to copy it and keep it somewhere safe.
당신만의 비밀이니까 복사해서 안전한 곳에 보관해야 해요
We will use it in just a second.
잠시 후에 쓸게요
Once you've done that, we'll be ready to actually put this key to use.
그렇게 하고 나면 이 키를 실제로 사용할 준비가 되죠 Put it
And we are almost there.
거의 다 왔어요
We are almost done.
거의 다 됐어요
So with any luck, you have now got a secret key copied.
운이 좋다면 비밀 열쇠를 복사할 수 있죠
You've forked out $5 or local currency equivalent and you're ready to go.
5달러나 그 지역 통화와 같은 액수를 내면 준비 완료죠
And I will see you in the next video for the very final step of setting up our environment.
다음 비디오에서 뵙죠 환경 설정의 마지막 단계에서요